<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles on ppcamp</title>
    <link>https://ppcamp.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles on ppcamp</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ppcamp.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>gRPC &amp; microservices in Go</title>
      <link>https://ppcamp.github.io/post/grpc-microservices/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ppcamp.github.io/post/grpc-microservices/</guid>
      <description>Brief introduction to microservices Database per service pattern SAGA pattern Orchestration Event-like gRPC Why use proxies? How to redirect? Best regards, @ppcamp </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Websocket</title>
      <link>https://ppcamp.github.io/post/websocket/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ppcamp.github.io/post/websocket/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s websocket? Websocket is a technology that is used to swap messages between two or more peers without create a HTTP request connection every time. It&amp;rsquo;s usually used to create real-time web applications, social network feeds, PWA and push notifications, chats, etc. In Ubuntu based distributions, for example, you can use a websocket server that will have a thread to every amount of time, refresh some data and trigger a new event, making system-calls to the notify-send program, which will show you a notification in your desktop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID’s report of Itabira city</title>
      <link>https://ppcamp.github.io/post/covid19-itabira/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ppcamp.github.io/post/covid19-itabira/</guid>
      <description>In this page I&amp;rsquo;ll try to explain to you how to built a simple script that generates a refreshed report basing on some spreadsheet. In this case, this file was used by Itabira&amp;rsquo;s health secretary. The project can be found here.
Context Since the first cases of the covid&amp;rsquo;s in Itabira, the Health Secretary ordered to generate a report to show to the citiziens what was happenning and the current situation of the city daily.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Graphql go</title>
      <link>https://ppcamp.github.io/post/graphql-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ppcamp.github.io/post/graphql-go/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s this so well know graphql? Go&amp;rsquo;tcha, I won&amp;rsquo;t discuss about this at all LoL.
Take a look in those articles below:
 https://www.moesif.com/blog/technical/graphql/REST-vs-GraphQL-APIs-the-good-the-bad-the-ugly/ https://blog.logrocket.com/why-you-shouldnt-use-graphql/ https://www.apollographql.com/docs/react/data/operation-best-practices/ https://graphql.org/ https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=epKhPB9PJqY&amp;amp;ab_channel=Simplilearn  But, personally, what I think about it:
Good points:
 It can be interesting when the amount of data of each request is relevant (mobile/lightweight apps) It can be interesting doing to the reuse of existent resolvers for our types (you&amp;rsquo;ll see an example in this project) It&amp;rsquo;s easier to the backend developer to handle with the errors (without worring about status codes, padronized response bodies and go on) It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to have a panel where you can see all available types/queries/mutations and its descriptions  Bad points:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Next posts</title>
      <link>https://ppcamp.github.io/post/next-posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ppcamp.github.io/post/next-posts/</guid>
      <description>What I plan to do next Bellow you can see what I want to do, following this order
 Itabira&amp;rsquo;s health secretariat ombudsman report: A script that access the spreadsheet and generates a report with plots. AFDN animator: How to build a simple afdn animator in rust Sigaa scrapper: A script that access the Sigaa&amp;rsquo;s system, and then, generates plots and infereces about it API&amp;rsquo;s builded in Golang (focused on speed) vs API&amp;rsquo;s focused in deployment time: A simple use case and personal thoughts about when using each one of them.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
